Let's discuss the advantages and disadvantages of Dublin Inc at less every node of Dublin could list
required extra space of any previous pointer, so it's possible to implement Dublin Link Atlas with
single pointer, though all operations requires an extra pointer previous to be maintained.
For example, in insertion, we need to modify the previous point or together with next notes.
At the end, doubly linked list can be traversed in both forward and backward direction.
So we have discussed that this advantages.
Now let's talk about the advantages it can be traversed in both forward and backward direction that
the lead operation in Dublin link at least, is more efficient.
If pointer to the node to be deleted is given, it's very simple when we are going to discuss these
and exercises and next visit.
We can quickly insert a new note before a given node in singly linked list to delete in node pointer
to the previous node is need to get this previous node.
Sometimes the list is traversed in double the link list.
We can get the previous node using the previous pointer, so it's very simple.
Think about in node that you can't contain and that contains data and you can get that next and the
previous very simple.
So you can directly the insert, delete and so on.
OK.
So all the operation required an extra pointer previous to be maintained.
This is that this advantages and require extra space.
OK.
There any data structure in this course or in life have this advantages and the advantages of this data
structure over other data structures.
So when you asked in the exam or in an interview to to get and write and ID like create a and data structure,
you'd think about what you need from this data structure.